# Parbhat Puri

## Software Developer

Kurukshetra - 136 128 - India https://parbhatpuri.com • https://github.com/parbhat

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Developer with an emphasis on performance, best practices and testing in order to create better applications. My experience primarily lies with the Python Programming language, Django (a Python web framework) as well as a wide range of other tools.

Remote work culture in companies helps me to work with the engineering teams across the globe like USA, Europe etc. By working with various teams, I learned clear communication and documentation are as important as the code itself. Therefore I always maintain clear communication with team members on my projects.

I like to involve in everything from the overall direction of a project, to design, user experience, and the actual implementation. I enjoy working on open source projects as it helps to give back to the community. I'm passionate about crafting great user experiences. And this influences all of my decisions as I work on a project.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### • Freelance Software Developer

June 2016 - Present

- I started as a part-time Freelance developer and later turned into full time. Working as a consultant helps to work with a range of companies of size from 3-4 people to more than 500 employees. Its been a great experience working with different tech teams from across the globe. Worked on projects for startups, government, established companies and charities. Primarily works as a backend developer with technologies like Python, Django and also work with JavaScript, SCSS.

Major clients include: The Motley Fool, Torchbox, Creative it development, Carpe.

## • Software Developer, ChrisDev Limited

June 2016 - November 2017

- After graduation, I continued to work with ChrisDev.
- Worked on the company's major projects like Registration System for Nationals Travelling Abroad and Conference Management System for the Trinidad and Tobago Ministry of Foreign and Caricom affairs.
- Built platform for company startup called Flybottle which helps socially conscious organisations to raise money online. Developed widgets to embed donation forms, fundraising goal graph on the organisation website. Admin interface to create new campaigns, manage donations, subscriptions etc. Donor interface to change the subscription amount, update payment method and cancel the subscription.
- Maintained Open Source projects of the company.

## • Full Stack Developer Intern, ChrisDev Limited

April 2015 - May 2016

- Remote position performed in the summer vacation and 4th year of my college. The internship was initially for 3 months and later became a member of the development team.
- I was paid to work on Open Source projects. Founder of the company is the supporter
  of Open Source. Therefore the internship started with a new open source project named
  Wagtail cookiecutter Foundation. And contributed to existing open source projects of the
  company like django-pandas.
- Designed and developed client projects using technologies like Python, Django, Wagtail CMS, AngularJS, Sass, etc.

## **OPEN SOURCE**

- Python Pedia: One stop for Python Programming resources. It's all about Python.
- Pelican Blue: Responsive theme for Pelican Static Site generator, powered by Python.
- Cookiecutter Django Foundation: Fork of Cookiecutter Django based on Zurb Foundation.
- Django Pandas: Tools for working with Pandas in Django projects.
- Django Pandas examples: Some examples of iPython/Jupyter Notebooks for django-pandas.
- Wagtail Cookiecutter Foundation: A Cookiecutter template for Wagtail using Zurb Foundation.
- Django Wagtail Feeds: Adds support for RSS and JSON Feeds to Wagtail CMS projects.
- Django Foundation formtags: Template tags for working with Foundation Forms in Django.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python backend development: Django, Flask, Wagtail (CMS)

Frontend development: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Vue, Foundation for sites, Bootstrap

**Databases:** MySql, PostgreSQL macOS, GNU/Linux **Version Control:** Git, mercurial

#### **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2016 B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

SHRI MATA VAISHNO DEVI UNIVERSITY, Jammu

CGPA: 7.53/10

2012 CBSE XII Examination , TAGORE PUBLIC SCHOOL, KURUKSHETRA

Percentage: 89.8%

2010 CBSE X Examination , TAGORE PUBLIC SCHOOL, KURUKSHETRA

CGPA: 9/10

## **ACHIEVEMENTS & POSITIONS HELD**

- CBSE Merit Scholarship: Central Sector Scheme of Scholarship for College and University students (CSSS-2012).
- Speaker for Github Workshop in Software Freedom Day 2015. The Workshop covers git version control system(VCS) and git workflow to contribute to an Open Source project on github.
- Coordinated Software Freedom Day 2015 and was responsible to manage the overall event.
- Speaker for Python Workshop in Software Freedom Day 2014. The Workshop covers basics and importance of Python Programming language.
- Initiated a Technical environment in the University by forming clubs like *Codechef campus chapter, PyClub* and organising various Workshops.

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**

ADDRESS: Kurukshetra, 136 128, Haryana, India

PHONE: +91 9468315914 SKYPE: parbhat.puri

EMAIL: me@parbhatpuri.com
WEBSITE: https://parbhatpuri.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/parbhat

GITHUB: https://github.com/parbhat
TWITTER: https://twitter.com/parbhatpuri
SLIDES: http://slides.com/parbhat